# **XUAN ZHANG**

(617) 286-9618 | xxuzhang92@gmail.com

# PUBLIC HEALTH ASSOCIATE

A public health associate possessing strong program management skills, and highly experienced in providing analysis and research in areas where the public health is affected. Experience in Epidemiology and Biostatistics culled from pursuit of a Master of Public Health degree, and high-level administration assistance to health-related projects including Infectious Diseases, Kidney disorders, and Diabetes. Developed an aptitude for patient assistance and disease transmission through clinical rotation and volunteering with national and international public health initiatives. Proficient in STATA, SAS, SPSS, VB, and Microsoft Office - Access, Word, Excel.

- Public Health Administration
- Data Extraction & Management
- Questionnaire Design
- Statistical Software

- Project Management
- Literature Review
- Strategic Planning/Analysis
- Teamwork

- Research
- Report Editing
- Sales Management
- English (Fluent), Mandarin

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Program Assistant

## MPH Capstone Project, JHSPH, Baltimore, MD

October 2013- Present

- Reviewed literature, edited a research paper and performed extensive research of the "Access to the Utilizations of Community Health Workers' Service project of Bangladesh from 1995 to 1998."
- Merged, synthesized dataset of more than 7000 households in Bangladesh using STATA, SAS.
- Descriptive analysis of health workers' service on family planning (contraceptive use, breast feeding).
- Constructing SES scales using Principle Components Analysis and analyzed the association of SES and health service delivery.

# Graduate Research Assistant, Community Based Primary Care Literature Reviewer

JHSPH, Baltimore

August 2013-Present

- Reviewed articles of Community Based Primary Health Care (CBPHC).
- Extracted detailed information and data, and finished the review forms independently.

#### Public Health Intern

### Centers for Disease Control, Shanghai, China

May 2013-June 2013

- Performed follow-up, surveillance, data management for non-infectious chronic diseases.
- Reviewed literature and extracted information for non-infectious diseases in Baoshan District.
- Edited paper of burden for Colorectal Carcinoma study.
- Developed aptitude for Statistical software Excel, Access, SPSS.

## HIV Research Assistant

#### Centers for Disease Control, Tianjin, China

November 2011-October 2012

- Assisted the program through research and review of literature and associated meta-analysis.
- Extracted, analyzed data from papers and generated reports for leadership.

#### Research Lead

### East Hospital of Tongji University, Shanghai

May 2011-May 2012

- Served as Research Lead for "The Influence of Atorvastatin on the Arterial Elasticity of Coronary Heart Disease Patients with or without Diabetes" project.
- Designed the study, screened and grouped the patients based on their medical history.
- Collected, analyzed the testing data and medical history information.
- Assisted physicians and patients for testing of Brachial-Ankle Pulse Wave Velocity (baPWV).

#### Project Associate

### Tongji University, Shanghai

May 2010-May 2011

- Provided research and review for the "Investigation of Spine Diseases among University Students" project.
- Conducted literature review for 40 papers and summarized the state-of-the-art research on spine diseases.
- Designed questionnaires, collected and analyzed the data.

XUAN ZHANG Resume, Page 2

Additional experience includes MPH practicum at Harvard Medical School and Johns Hopkins University with experience of outcome research of Chronic Kidney Disease, Medical Rotation at the University of Nebraska Medical Center, East Hospital of Tongji University, Shanghai, and Medical Internship at Heilongjiang Province Hospital, Harbin, China Sept. 2009- June 2013

#### **EDUCATION & CREDENTIALS**

Master of Public Health (MPH), Concentration: Epidemiology and Biostatistics, GPA: 3.74/4.00

Johns Hopkins Bloomberg School of Public Health (JHSPH), Baltimore, MD

Expected May 2014

### Bachelor of Medicine (MD Equivalent), GPA: 3.45/4.00, Rank 4/74

Tongji University, Shanghai, China, June 2013 Honors: Shanghai Outstanding Graduates, National Scholarship in China

#### VOLUNTEERISM

# Prevention Through Education (NGO), Chicago

HIV Consultant online Volunteer Sept. 2012- Present

- Consultant for people having HIV related issues
- Assisted managers maintaining website
- Coordinated volunteers and customers

# Annual Shanghai SINO-US Family Medicine Symposium, Shanghai, China October 2012

Family Medicine Trainee and Volunteer

- Awarded the Certificate of Standardization of Primary Care and Training
- Volunteered in the symposium and received the scholars in family medicine from worldwide

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- Liming Zhu, Xuan Zhang, Xin Li. Analysis of Epidemiological Trend for the Colorectal Cancer death and YPLL in Baoshan District of Shanghai. Journal of Environmental & Occupational Medicine, Submitted
- Wang Xu, Cao Sirui, Xuan Zhang, Fang Hongxia, Wang Xiaoqing, Fu Yanyong, Pang Xuewen, Zhan Siyan. A
  Systematic Review about Therapeutic Regimen in Death Rate of TB/HIV Co-infected Patients China Chronic Diseases
  Prevention and Control, Vol 21 (2), April, 2013
- Xuan Zhang, Haibin Zhang. The Understanding of Cause and Treatment of Cervical Dystonia, Yanbian Medicine, ISSN 1674-9855, CN22-1181/R, page 372, Vols. 6 (6), June, 2012
- Xuan Zhang, Zuanshen Chen, Xinglun Liang. Family Medicine in the UK, USA and Australia and Its Implications for China, Yiyao Qianyan (Advanced Medicine), Vols. 2011, 01(24)
- Xuan Zhang. The Influence of Atorvastatin on the Arterial Elasticity of CHD Patients with or without DM, Overseas English, ISSN 1009-5039, CN 34-1209/g4, page 285-286, Vols. 17, September, 2012